hey guys Pastor Ivor Myers here and in
today's video we're going to be taking a
look at a Biblical mathematical
challenge for atheists and agnostics
let's jump in
all right so what is this biblical
mathematical challenge for agnostics and
atheists
we are going to be looking at a very
specific challenge a challenge that if
you're an atheist or an agnostic I can
promise you it is likely that you have
never heard this before in fact if
you're a Christian I can promise you it
is highly likely that you have never
heard this before as well so
I encourage you to listen to listen
carefully and to follow along closely
um when we talk about
um you know debating between
um
someone who believes in the Bible and an
atheist and agnostic there's a lot of
arguments that are presented that
usually end up falling flat we're not
going to be using any of those arguments
in this presentation in fact
um let's go to the screen and I just
want to share with you three things that
you are not going to hear in this
presentation number one bias reasonings
so what is bias reasoning many people
are what they are simply because it was
the predominant religion in the area in
which they were brought up in they were
brought up their parents told them you
know Islam is the way and you must be a
Muslim Christianity is the way you must
be a Christian whatever the religion is
a lot of people are what they are simply
because that's how they were brought
they were brought up they have no
understanding of their religion and if
you ask them they're just like look
that's what I am leave me alone I don't
discuss religion
that was never a good enough reason for
me by the way I was a skeptic before I
became a Christian I didn't become a
Christian until I was 19 years old being
a skeptic of the Bible it was not until
I was 19 20 years old that I saw
something that totally revolutionized
my whole thinking process and led me to
become a Christian
so you're not going to hear biased
reasoning from me again I believe a lot
of people could not could not explain to
you why why are you a Baptist instead of
a Catholic why are you uh a Methodist
instead of a
Anglican
a lot of people don't know why they are
what they are
and so
as a skeptic of of religion this is one
of the things that mainly I was like
y'all don't even know why you are what
you are you're just saying I am this and
leave me alone right and that kind of
turned me off from religion all together
number two personal experience I would
remember hearing people say things like
you know I was an alcoholic and when I
gave my life to God things change and
that's how I know God is real the god of
the Bible well what about Muslims who
had the same experience what about
Muslims who are alcoholics before they
became Muslims and when they when they
read the Quran they had this
life-changing experience again
these kinds of reasonings were just kind
of like
mind-numbing to me like how do you argue
that when they're people of other
religions who have the same
type of testimony this is why I became a
Buddhist this is why I uh you know
became this religion of that religion
that was not good enough reason
to to
say this is why I am what I am this is
why I believe in God so I'm not going to
be using any of those neither am I going
to be using reason number three which is
the argument of science right the world
couldn't possibly be here without a
designer without uh uh a Divine
intelligence
um I think there is there is Merit to
that argument to a certain degree but it
doesn't answer the question of which
Divine intelligence
doesn't answer the question that it's
the god of the Bible or the God of this
religion or the god of that religion
doesn't answer that question so again
even if that word approved that there is
a God in existence it doesn't tell us
which God my challenge to you today this
mathematical challenge I believe proves
definitively number one that there is a
God and number two which God that God is
um let me read from a book called 50
reasons people give for believing in a
god it's written by Guy P Harrison who
himself is a skeptic right uh he's
agnostic and
he's giving he's laying out 50 reasons
people he typically give 50 arguments
people typically give for you know
arguing the existence of God and he's
just shooting them down one by one but
there is one argument that he discusses
where he says now if someone could prove
this then I would believe so let's check
out what that argument is
under the uh section entitled ancient
prophecies prove my God exists Harrison
writes this like most atheists I am not
insane and I do not like pain believe me
I don't want to suffer in anyone's
health for all eternity
that's a whole different discussion on
its own we're going to address that some
other time does the bible teach
that the wicked go to hell for all
eternity but I digress let's keep
reading if there were just one precise
and detailed prediction that came true
and could be explained as the work of a
God no matter if it were in the Bible
the Quran and it goes on to list you
know other sources he says listen
doesn't matter where it comes from I
would not ignore it or deny it
he says if gods are real and they want
to impress all of us with their
prophecies then why don't they make the
prediction obvious to everyone including
well-meaning Skeptics then he goes on to
give an example of what he thinks a
prophecy genuine prophecy would look
like now he says if a Believer can show
me a prophecy with that kind of detail
I'm on board with their religion sign me
up that's powerful coming from a skeptic
of the Bible a skeptic of religion
he's saying because he acknowledges that
it is humanly impossible to accurately
predict the future
you know of course if you have
scientific markers right like scientific
tools we can predict the weather uh you
know there are certain things we can
predict with a fair amount of accuracy
but we cannot do it
from a sort of innate ability that's
humanly impossible so so therefore he's
like look if someone could show me
something that could genuinely be
considered prophecy
and we're going to qualify this you guys
so trust me for some of you uh Skeptics
and atheists and agnostics I hear you
already right I hear you saying I've
heard you know Christians argue prophecy
before but there's so many problems with
that and we're going to address those
problems all right because I get it I
just want you to follow I just want you
to listen okay
he goes on to say
but
such predictions simply do not exist the
ones we have are vague or too easily
explained as events that could have
occurred without the involvement of a
God so his final position is if these
prophecies actually existed I would
believe but they don't exist his belief
is that they don't exist along with many
other Skeptics many other atheists why
because if it did exist
it would be the strongest evidence
listen to me y'all not science not
personal experience
prophecy would be the strongest evidence
of a Divine intelligence I want to read
from another book this one is by Douglas
E Krueger also an agnostic or an atheist
and in his book what is atheism a short
intro introduction he presents five
criteria to judge so-called prophecy now
again he doesn't believe that it exists
either but either but he says listen if
prophecy is to be considered genuine
these are the five criteria it must meet
number one he says the prophecy must be
clear and it must contain sufficient
detail to make its fulfillment by a wide
variety of possible events unlikely in
other words you can't have multiple
fulfillments multiple possibilities
number two the event that can fulfill
the prophecy must be unusual or unique
number three the prophecy must be known
to have been made before the event that
is supposed to be its fulfillment I must
speak a little bit more to this later
but we not we have to understand we have
to know if it's a genuine prophecy that
it was made before the event that is
supposed to be its fulfillment came to
pass
one of the issues that many Skeptics
have when it when Christians attempt to
use prophecy
is they will use what I'll call internal
prophecy and fulfillment in other words
they'll take a text from the book of
Exodus or Leviticus or numbers and say
look this text pointed to Jesus and
they'll go to the Book of Matthew Mark
Luke or John to show the Fulfillment of
the prophecy and they'll say see don't
you believe now
now you guys listen if you believe in
the Bible
if you believe in the Bible then that's
a solid argument if you do not believe
in the Bible you cannot use the Bible
to demonstrate prophecy that is
fulfilled in the Bible
why because a skeptic and agnostic and
an atheist and atheist do not they don't
believe in the Bible
so you can't use the Bible to prove the
Bible
and this is what happens so often so
when when Skeptics hear
a Christian about to mention prophecy
and especially this type of internal
prophecy it's just like it's circular
reasoning
all right so let's keep reading
the event foretold must not be of the
sort that could be the result of an
educated guess number five the event
that fulfills the prophecy cannot be
staged or the relevant circumstances
manipulated by those aware of the
prophecy in such a way as to
intentionally cause the prophecy to be
fulfilled in other words a bunch of
people can't get up and say hey you know
what the prophecy says this is supposed
to happen so let's make it happen it's
got to be outside of the of the hands of
humanity right this prophecy if it's
going to be genuine must be of the sort
that it could not be manipulated by
those aware of the prophecy what the
prophecy means
they're not going to be able to say hey
the prophecy says this so let's make it
come to pass the prophecy has to be too
large a scale
of events
that it could not be manipulated by by a
single individual a group of individuals
even a nation
even a bunch of individuals okay
um so
he goes on to say unfortunately for the
Christian not a single case of supposed
Bible prophecy can satisfy the criteria
I'm going to demonstrate that this is
wrong
I'm going to demonstrate that
this man along with many other Skeptics
and atheists agnostics who hold this
position hold that position because they
are unaware
of what I'm about to share with you in
this video
all right let me share with you just a
little bit more on Prophecy so that you
will know what I'm not going to do
let's take Nostradamus for example
Nostradamus is a uh was considered a a
prophet someone who predicted many
events and if you've ever read any of
nostradamus's work one thing you'll know
is that they are so vague that you could
make them mean anything for example here
is one near the gates and within two
cities there will be two scourges the
like of which was never seen famine with
play Within plague people put out by
Steel crying to the great Immortal God
for relief now some people believe that
this is Nostradamus predicting covet
wow we have no
no key given by Nostradamus to help us
understand what he means by Gates what
does he mean by Gates what two cities
what two scorges
scores that have never been seen before
how do we measure that famine within
playing what does that mean put out by
the put out by Steel is still symbolic
is it literal what are we talking about
here this is an example a good example
of vague prophecy you're not going to
hear me do that
you're not going to hear the Bible do
that
in this presentation I'm going to show
you something some things that are
Beyond way be that that more than
fulfill more than surpass or meet the
criteria given
for genuine prophecy
okay how about this let's take the Quran
so you will hear Muslims often say that
the Quran is full of Prophecy the Quran
prophesied this is the Quran prophesied
that and here's a couple examples I'll
just pull this from off the internet
um roads in the mountains so Muslims
many Muslims believe that the Quran
prophesied roads in mountains the text
they use and when the mountains are made
to move and hear from uh from uh
actually a Muslim web website it says
centuries before the invention of
dynamite the Holy Quran prophesied the
blowing up and the moving of the
mountains now
how this verse translates to mountains
being blown up and roads being placed in
mountains I could not tell you I could
not explain
this would be a good example of making
stuff up
right I'm just gonna make this mean
something that will make it look like
prophecy is fulfilled I'm going to say
see look the Quran fulfills prophecy
how about this one new transportation
systems and when the sea camel 10 months
pregnant are abandoned
and here's another one and he has
created horses and mules and asses that
they may ride them and as a source of
beauty and he will create what you do
not yet know
again
how does this
translate into prophecy of a new
transport system how do we get that from
these verses you have to imply you have
to impose there's a lot you need to do
to walk away and say look the Quran so
many years ago prophesied that they were
going to be that there was going to be a
new transport system
it really doesn't make sense
it really doesn't add up
as we know it says people especially
those living in the deserts have now
abandoned camels and other animals for
traveling but this prophecy of invention
and emergence of new Transport Systems
is ongoing as we witness new and faster
modes of transportation emerging all the
time
honestly
um
this would do nothing to convince me
that the Quran actually prophesied a new
system of Transportation or roads in the
mountains okay so we're not going to be
doing that we're not going to be looking
at vague prophecies like this as I
mentioned before even within
Christianity
we are not going to be looking at
circular reasoning meaning we're not
going to use the Bible to prove the
Bible now
we are going to be looking at the Bible
but I'm not going to use the Bible to
prove the Bible we're going to be
looking at secular history
to prove
prophecy found in the Bible
prophecy that extends outside of the
time of the writing of the Bible so
we're going to be looking at events
foretold in the Bible in Bible times and
these events we're looking at go way
beyond the Bible meaning we can't use
the Bible
to verify these prophecies the only
thing we can depend on is secular
history
so again pulled from a website
um it talks about a statistical
improbability here's what it says some
Bible scholars suggest that there are
more than 300 Old Testament prophetic
scriptures completed in the life of
Jesus Christ circumstances such as his
birthplace lineage and the method of
execution were Beyond Christ control and
could not have been accidentally or
deliberately fulfilled in his book
science speaks Peter Stoner and Robert
Newman discuss the statistical and
probability of one man whether
accidentally or deliberately fulfilling
just eight of the prophecies Jesus
fulfilled now again
I'm reading this simply to say we're not
going to be doing this because this is a
perfect example of taking Prophecy in
the Bible and then using the Bible to to
say look it was fulfilled for the
skeptic all the skeptic is going to say
is this was written in to make it look
like Jesus fulfilled these prophecies
that's all it's the same book if I go if
I open a book and in the beginning of
the book it says this thing is going to
be fulfilled and in the end of the book
it says it was fulfilled and the whole
book is fiction what good does that do
for anyone
right you're using the very same source
to try to prove the authenticity of that
source and I get that argument listen if
you believe in the Bible then these
prophecies are fully meaningful to us
I believe in the Bible I believe there
are more than 300 prophecies that were
fulfilled in Christ I believe all that
but for a skeptic for one who does not
believe in the Bible that's not gonna
work
okay
so
um with that in mind we're going to be
looking at four mathematical challenges
four prophecies found in the Bible these
are the prophecy of Daniel 2 Daniel 7
Revelation 11 and Revelation chapter 13.
these are the four prophecies and each
one of these is going to present a
mathematical problem for the agnostic a
mathematical challenge for the agnostics
so let's begin the first one we're going
to deal with is the prophecy entitled
Nebuchadnezzar's dream found in Daniel
chapter 2.
now before we begin we've got to
establish
dating of the Book of Daniel
for those who believe in the
authenticity of the Book of Daniel they
I should say we believe the book was
written in the 6th Century right during
the time of the Babylonian Empire
but for Skeptics of the Book of Daniel
they believe the book was written in the
second century
during the time of the Grecian Empire
and maybe a little bit into the Roman
and the reason they believe this is
because
they do not believe
that the prophecies found in the Book of
Daniel
are actually genuine
there's no way that someone could have
known ahead of time the things that are
revealed in this book so they say nah
the book was written in the Grecian
Empire and that's how we can explain
that the author knew these things
because he wrote them as if they were
prophecy but he had the knowledge of it
already in his mind so this is history
for him but he's writing it as if it
were prophecy and that's why they give
the Book of Daniel the second century
date during the Grecian Empire
for the sake of our
approach you're going to see it doesn't
matter whether the book was written in
the second set in the sixth Century or
the second century you're going to see a
literally makes minimal difference
so as we go through this prophecy for
the skeptic who says Ah the book was
written in the second century
will
I will give you that even though I
disagree with that we're gonna just keep
both of those dates on the table and I'm
gonna show you how it makes literally no
difference so let's begin
Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon has a
dream he forgets the dream but
he's eventually told by the Prophet
Daniel what he dreamed and the meaning
of the dream so in this dream he sees a
statue or an image of a man whose head
is of gold his chest and arms of silver
his belly and dies of brass his legs of
iron and then his toes of iron and clay
and while he's watching this in his
scene is in his dream a stone cut out
without hands comes out of the sky and
destroys the image on the feet destroys
the entire image and then a mountain
grows in its place
so we can do one of two things we can
say uh that's a vague prophecy it means
nothing it's a dream didn't even have we
can do all that or we can actually look
at the Bible to see does the bible
contain a key that helps us to
understand what's going on what this
Vision represents
and the answer is yes
in Daniel chapter 2 verse 38 Daniel
writes these words and wheresoever the
children of men dwell he's explaining to
nebuchadnezz of the dream
and he says this and wheresoever the
children of men dwell the Beast of the
field and the files of the heaven has he
given into thine hand and has made thee
ruler over them all thou art this head
of gold so what I want you to see here
is there's no room
for misinterpretation there's no room
for guessing there's no room to say ah
it could mean anything because we are
told
that the head of gold
represents
Nebuchadnezzar and his kingdom
in fact
Daniel goes on to say
in verse 39 and after these shall arise
another kingdom inferior to thee and
another third Kingdom of brass which
shall bear rule over all the earth and
the fourth Kingdom shall be strong as
iron so what we know here is that these
four metals these the the head of gold
the chestnuts of silver the Bellion
thighs of brass the legs of iron
represent four kingdoms so they don't
represent four different types of food
we can't make these mean anything or
they represent you know four different
baseball teams no we are told
specifically they represent four
kingdoms and we know that the first
Kingdom the the prophecy tells us the
first kingdom is the kingdom of Babylon
Babylon ruled from 605 to 539 BC so now
we just ask ourselves a simple question
was there a kingdom that came on the
scene that oh overthrew the Babylonian
Kingdom and the answer is yes it was the
middle Persian Empire which ruled from
539 BC to 331 BC you can check this out
in history
if the Book of Daniel was written in the
6th Century BC like I believe it was
then
what we have here is Daniel accurately
foretelling the fall of a superpower to
another Power
he's foretelling that Babylon is going
to fall and another Nation a nation of
silver by the way interestingly enough
Babylon was rich in gold medal Persia
was particularly rich in silver keep
this in mind
mino-persia rules from 539 to 331 BC was
there a kingdom that overthrew the
medo-persian Empire the answer is yes
there was a third Kingdom that kingdom
is the kingdom of Greece which ruled
from 331 BC to 168 BC so Babylon would
be the head of gold medal Persia would
be the chest and arms of silver and then
the belly and thighs of brass would
represent the Grecian Kingdom the Greece
and Empire
now we we're simply left with one
question was there a fourth Kingdom that
overthrew the third the answer is yes
the legs of iron would come to represent
the Roman Empire the Roman Empire ruled
from 168 BC to
476 A.D
I want y'all to catch this
because
what we have here
is over a thousand years
of History
keep that number in mind
in Daniel 2 41 it says and whereas thou
saw to defeat and Toes were part
Potter's clay and part of iron the
kingdom shall be divided now here's the
here's the interesting thing y'all
Daniel could have said and after the
fourth Kingdom a fifth Kingdom shall
arise which shall overthrow the fort he
doesn't say that
what he says is that this fourth Kingdom
would be divided and the question I have
for you is what happened to Rome the
Empire of Rome after it fell was it
overthrown by another kingdom was it
overthrown by some other Nation the
answer is no it was divided among
various Barbarian tribes now I need you
all the catches because Daniel could
have been on a roll right uh you know
Babylon is going to fall to another
kingdom that King is going to fall to a
third Kingdom that third kingdom is
going to fall to a fourth Kingdom that
fourth kingdom is going to fall to a
fifth Kingdom no he says the fourth
kingdom is going to be divided
remember ten toes
if you look at this map of ancient Rome
as it's being divided you will note on
this map you can look this map up online
you will not on this map that there are
in essence 10 Barbarian tribes
you have the vandals and you have the
Visa gods and you have the sway VI and
you have the burgundians and the
alameini and the ostrogas and the herily
and the Lombards and the Franks and the
Saxons now I need you to understand that
while these tribes were were
sacking Rome if you will and dividing
Rome amongst themselves
uh many of these tribes combined with
smaller tribes and you know they might
just be known as the vice but within the
vice of gods they were several smaller
tribes uh these tribes formed
confederacies but ultimately they were
broken down into 10 various kingdoms
now I need you to catch the significance
of this because again
the prophet who writes the book of
Daniel accurately foretells in these
toes of iron and Clay this this breaking
down of this fourth Kingdom and then
there is this clay element that is
introduced into this Vision this
prophecy what does this clay represent
remember gold
silver brass iron and then in the toes
meaning
Rising among these ten kingdoms would be
this clay Kingdom now are we left to
just surmise or what could this clay
Kingdom represent what would it be no
we're not the Bible tells us what clay
represents notice with me Isaiah 64
verse 8 which says this but now oh Lord
Thou Art Our Father we are the clay and
thou our Potter and we are all the work
of thine hand
in the Bible
clay is used to represent the people
of God the professed people of God those
who profess to have God as their father
You Are The Potter we're the clay you're
able to mold us we can see this again in
Jeremiah chapter 8 and verse 16 or House
of Israel can I do cannot cannot I do
with you as this part of saith the Lord
behold as the clay is in The Potter's
hand so you are are you in my hand or
House of Israel so what we see here
is among these 10
Barbarian tribes
there would rise a spiritual Kingdom
professing
to belong to God
and my question to you atheist agnostic
is this
is there a spiritual Kingdom
that rolls in the place of the Roman
Empire
when Rome fell when the Western Roman
Empire fell in 476 A.D
the recognized date of the fall of Rome
the Roman Empire
was there a spiritual entity that would
a spiritual Kingdom that would grow to
take its place now if you're being
honest with history
you realize the answer is yes the
question again becomes how is it that a
book written in the 6th Century or the
second century could accurately foretell
this history
because it's not humanly possible
it isn't World Atlas online you can
Google this I just want you to check
this out because I need you to
understand something what does clay do
remember when we were kids and we would
play with Clay you know create you know
little clay would stick together watch
this y'all the Holy Roman Empire is
traditionally believed to have been
established by Charlemagne in 800 A.D it
ruled over much of Western and Central
Europe from the 9th to the 19th century
until the its dissolution in 1806 during
the Napoleonic Wars however the Holy
Roman Empire wasn't unified in the same
way that many of the other Empires were
it was more of a collection of sovereign
Nations existing together in a Loosely
defined Alliance the glue the glue the
clay the glue that held the empire
together was the Catholic Church which
had which had the authority to name the
emperor so I need y'all to catch this in
Daniel 2 this kingdom is described as
clay and here we have a totally secular
Source World Atlas simply saying not
thinking hey let me use Bible language
but simply saying the Catholic church
was the glue that held these kingdoms
together
so what is our first mathematic problem
if we take the 6th Century date of this
book what we have
is over
2600 years of History accurately
foretold why do I say 2600 years history
because Beloved the prophecy says that
these kingdoms would not they would try
to reunite but they would not be able to
reunite into a single Empire as before
476 A.D
that's why it's divided it's described
as clay and iron the kingdom will be
partly strong partly broken you could
read it in Daniel 2.
to this very day
Europe has never reunited in that way
so this prophecy extends down to our
very day what we have is over 2600 years
of history and the question becomes how
did Daniel accurately predict let's look
at the five criteria again
can't be something that is could be an
educated guess
prophecy has to be given long before the
event to take place what's fulfilled
must be unique
must not be vague
come on y'all
this passes all the criteria listed in
both books as what a genuine prophecy
looks like could not be manipulated so
it couldn't be like the Romans were like
hey you know what the prophecy says that
when we fall we can't be
overthrown by another kingdom so maybe
let's talk to these Barbarian tribes and
see if they will we can you know kind of
set it up to where Rome gets divided
instead of Falls to one other Nation
the the the middle president Empire
wasn't thinking ah you know what the
prophecy says that we're supposed to
fall to Greece so we better not fight
back we you know if the prophecy says
this they probably not even reading the
prophecy which one of these kingdoms are
like yeah let's what else does the
prophecy say what else does the Bible
say come on
you see the problem
the mathematical problem that a an
atheist and agnostic must answer is how
do these 2600 years of History get laid
out so perfectly by a human
how does this human have this kind of
knowledge to accurately foretell this
future now for those Skeptics who say no
the book was written in the second
century BC okay you cut it down to over
2100 years
do you see what I mean when I say
whether you say 6th Century or second
century it makes no difference
because you're still talking about
thousands of years at least 2 000 years
of History accurately foretold so that's
just one that's Daniel too
we haven't gotten to Daniel 7 yet but
we're about to get there now so let's go
Daniel chapter seven are you good
hold that hold that equation because man
we're going to look at another equation
we're going to go to Daniel chapter
seven
and in Daniel chapter 7 now Daniel has a
dream and in this dream he sees four
beasts the first is like a lion with
eagles wings the second like a bear with
three ribs in his mouth the third is
like a leopard with four wings and four
heads and the fourth is this
non-descript Beast that has ten horns
but it also has great iron teeth now is
this prophecy up to interpretation is it
just garbage is it they does it fit any
of the criteria
that we can eliminate it as a genuine
prophecy well
listen in Daniel 7 verse 23 we are told
what these beasts represent
thus he said the fourth Beast shall be
the fourth Kingdom upon the Earth which
shall be diverse from all kingdoms and
shall Devour the whole earth it shall
tread it down and break it in pieces so
now we know
that these beasts represent kingdoms
they don't represent baseball teams they
don't represent basketball teams we
can't make it mean anything no no no no
no they represent kingdoms and Daniel
tells us that the fourth Beast
represents
the fourth Kingdom
so what do we know here
what we can know here is that this
fourth beast in Daniel 7 which
represents the fourth Kingdom must be
the same as the legs of iron in Daniel
2. in other words four Kingdoms in
Daniel 2 head of gold Chestnut on the
silver billion thighs of brass legs of
iron are gonna parallel The Lion The
Bear the leopard and this fourth Beast
how do we know this once again the
fourth Beast has ten horns the Ted the
the legs have ten toes
are y'all following
so now you can tell me I don't have to
ask you you can tell me who is the lion
oh the lion must be the same as the head
of gold Babylon who is the bear oh the
bear must be the same as the
um the a chest and on the silver that
must be Greece if the legs of iron is
Rome all we got to do is work our way
back
head of gold
the the lion Babylon the bear
medo-persia
the four-headed leopard Greece now
here's what's interesting
when Alexander the Great conquered the
medo-persian Empire he died shortly
thereafter and his empire was divided
amongst four generals four heads
they were Cassandra lesimicus Ptolemy
and seleuces now again y'all if Daniel
is writing his book in the 6th Century
BC how in the world is he accurately
predicting that the Grecian Empire would
break down into four generals that would
ultimately begin to war amongst
themselves
how is he accurately predicting that
so we've got the four-headed leopard
that's those with the foreheads
represent and then you got the the the
the fourth Beast which is symbolic of
the kingdom of Rome the fourth Beast has
ten horns which are gonna parallel the
The Divided nations of Europe
after the fall of the Roman Empire
and then we're told about this
little horn that would rise after the
ten horns here's what the Bible says in
Daniel 7 24.
follow me closely because this is going
to introduce us to our second math
problem Daniel 7 24 and the ten horns
out of this kingdom are ten kings that
shall arise we already saw the map
these are the Ten Kings the Oscar Gods
the vice against the vandals the Franks
the herily ETC and another shot rise
after them and he shall be diverse from
the first and he saw subdue three kings
so now we can see something very clearly
if the lion parallels the head of gold
and the bear parallels the chestnuts of
silver and the leopard parallels the
belly and thighs of brass
and the fourth Beast with the iron teeth
parallel the legs of iron
and the Ten of horns parallel the
Barbarian tribes then the little horn
which comes up among the ten must
parallel the clay Kingdom in Daniel 2.
what we're seeing here beloved is that
Daniel 7
is amplifying what we saw in Daniel 2
but it's going to give us more detail
mathematical detail
so let's see what is this mathematical
detail again we know that this little
horn must represent the Roman Roman
Roman Catholic system rising out of the
Roman Empire listen
to what the Bible says here
and by the way before we get there
please note this
if this little horn is to wage war
against three of these ten kingdoms
what we need to understand is that if
the little horn is a religious power
then the war it wages is going to be on
religious grounds
can I do I let me say that again if the
little horn is a religious power
different from the ten horns it's Clay
not iron it claims to be molded by God
it claims to have been brought on the
scene by God if the little horn is going
to wage war against three of these ten
horns it must be a war based on
religious grounds now by the way I need
to mention this this is for the skeptic
and atheist in particular
that stone which ultimately represents
the kingdom of God coming down and
destroying this image destroys the image
on the feet not on the head not in the
chest and arms not on the uh belly and
thighs not on the legs but the feet of
iron and clay
why is it significant
because the feet of iron and Clay
represent the mingling of church and
state let me say that again the feet of
iron and Clay represent the mingling of
church and state
and whatever happens in this mingling of
church and state is so offensive to God
that the stone strikes the image on the
feet what I'm saying to you is as we
look at what happened during the Dark
Ages when the church began to dominate
and Rule
and take political Affairs into their
own matters we will see that it was
something that God did not sanction
and we're going to see that very clearly
here
as we go on to discover what this little
horn does so notice with me what this
little horn does according to uh to what
we just read in Daniel 7 that this
little horn would wage war against three
of the ten horns we just saw if it's a
religious power the little horn it must
be waging a war on religious grounds and
now the question is was there a
religious controversy between the ten
horns and the papacy and the answer is
yes it was called the Aryan controversy
let me read the Aryan controversy was a
series of Christian disputes about the
nature of Christ that began with a
dispute the most important of these
controversies concerned the relationship
between the substance of God the father
and the substance of his son in essence
this war this controversy this conflict
was a religious conflict that that was
going on between
papal Christianity and these Germanic
tribes who were also professing
Christianity but it was a difference it
was a conflict between the nature of God
and the nature of Christ let me read on
by the way all my slides are available
so if you if you I'm going to put a link
in this video so if you want a copy of
everything I'm reading you're gonna get
it okay let me read utterly defeated
in the Roman Empire arianism
received new life through its
implantation through the Germanic tribes
and with them we entered the Western
Empire so what we're seeing here is that
arianism
got a foothold through these Aryan
Germanic tribes I should say
why is that significant
when we get to 476
476.
which we just which we saw earlier was
the date of the fall of the Roman Empire
why is that they considered the fall of
the Roman Empire let me read the Battle
of Ravina capital of the Western Roman
Empire between the helioli under their
king or Odessa and the remnants of the
Western Roman army in Roman Italy
occurred in early September 476 and
represented a culminating event in the
ongoing fall of the Western Roman Empire
so the herily who were Aryan
conquered Rome
and with the fall of their Capital that
is why the date 476 is considered by
historians the fall of the Roman Empire
476. the herily are now controlling Rome
they are an Aryan tribe
okay let's keep reading
Zeno was the emperor of the Eastern
Roman Empire
in fact let me just jump here real quick
I want you to know this note this Xeno
in spite of his personal feelings came
to the throne as a champion of the
Catholic party you can see that from the
Catholic encyclopedia so what Xeno is
about to do here is on behalf of the
church watch this at the behest of Zeno
in 489 theodoric who was the King of the
ostrogothic Empire one of the ten horns
theodoric
of the ostragos attacked Odessa the king
of Italy emerging victorious in 493. so
what you have here is the Catholic
Church using one horn by the way the
Oster gods were also Aryan
but the church used them despite that to
try to remove the hairline from Italy
and here's what happened as a result
Ostro Gods begin to rule Italy and now
you got one problem that's that's has
replaced another harreli removed off the
scene that's one horn who were the
Vandals
differences between the Aryan vandals
and their trinitarian subjects including
both Catholics and donatists were a
constant source of tension in their
African State Catholic Bishops were
exiled or killed by geneseric and laymen
were executed from or excluded from
office and frequently suffered
confiscation of their property let me
jump down to that last sentence
generally most Vandal Kings accept
Hilder persecuted trinitarian Christians
to a greater or lesser extent Banning
conversion for vandals exiling Bishops
and generally making life difficult for
trinitarian so I'm painting a picture
here and what I want you to see is
number one that Harry lie was one horn
that stood in the way of the Roman
Catholic Church they were removed by the
Roman Catholic Church using the ostrogas
to defeat the heraldi but there were
also the vandals the vandals were were
very anti and they stayed toward the
Roman Catholic church and so as a result
of this check this out the next Emperor
we're going to read about in fact before
we get there let me read this from
Britannica uh the vandals were Arden
Aryan Christians and their persecution
of the Roman Catholic Church in Africa
were at times Fierce particularly during
the last years of the reign of gay
cerrick's successor human in 533 watch
this the the byzantines under belisarius
invaded North Africa following the
deposition by the usurper gelimer of
humeric sun hilderick who was a close
friend of the Byzantine emperor
Justinian the first
in one campaign season the vandals
kingdom was destroyed Rome again ruled
the area and restored the churches to
the Roman Catholics the vandals play no
further role in history watch this you
guys
the hairily removed by Emperor Zeno on
behalf of the church the vandals removed
by Emperor Justinian on behalf of the
church all surrounding their arianism
so what we saw according to the prophecy
was that this little horn would uproot
three horns basically in order to begin
dominating in some type of way
was there a third horn uprooted the
answer is yes
listen carefully
this religious division added to the
ethnic antagonism the
unification of the Roman and Barbarian
peoples but gradually the Catholic
Church succeeded in eliminating arianism
now let me just state for you that I am
not reading from prophetic sources here
like
these sources are not riding on behalf
of Prophecy they're just recording
history
notice what it says
but gradually the Catholic Church
succeeded in eliminating arianism in
some instances watch this now in some
instances this was achieved by military
action that all but wiped out the
Germanic element now watch this watch
which two tribes mentioned in 553 the
vandals in Africa were utterly destroyed
by the armies of Justinian on behalf of
the Catholic church and in 552 the
ostrogothic kingdom that same Kingdom
that was used years earlier to remove
the harioli by the Catholics that
Kingdom of Italy suffered a similar fate
other kingdoms by peaceful means and
through their action uh arianism Was
Defeated so in these other kingdoms
aaronism was defeated but it wasn't
about military force the prophecy that
this little horn would war against three
of these ten horns it would be a
religious War because we know that this
horn is religious in nature and lo and
behold what do you know the Roman
Catholic system through Emperor Zeno and
through Emperor Justinian uproot three
of those ten horns
we're not done
first horn hair rely second horn vandals
vandalic War third horn ostrogoths the
gothic Wars
now you tell me
how a prophet how a person
writing in the 6th Century BC or the
second century BC would have been able
to accurately foretell that history
listen to what else it says about this
little horn
he shall speak great words against the
most high and shall wear out or
persecute the Saints of the most high
and think to change times and laws and
they shall be given into his hand until
a time and times and the dividing of
time and that new math problem we're
about to look at it right now because
there's a time element given to this
prophecy
so hold on before we get there I need
you to see this
what does it mean that this little horn
would
think to change times and laws
interestingly enough
if you look at the writings of the
church here's just one the pope has
power to change times to abrogate laws
and to dispense with all things even the
precepts of Christ the pope has
Authority and is often exercises to
dispense with the command of Christ now
I want you to understand here
this is not
the Catholic Church saying how can we
fulfill prophecy in a negative sense oh
the Bible speaks of this power that's
going to speak uh uh um great words
against God
I mean what could those great words be
maybe like we have the power to forgive
sins
something that the Bible says only God
can do or how about Holy Father there's
only one Holy Father so for someone to
call himself God In the Flesh for
someone to call himself God on Earth the
Holy Father that's a pretty big
statement that's a pretty bold statement
but it doesn't stop there
will think to change times and laws it's
as if they were almost quoting from the
Bible without realizing it
what about the persecution although the
wearing others of the Saints no one
needs to question the history that
during the Dark Ages the Catholic Church
persecuted those that did not believe
as she did and if that's not enough
what laws did they change we are told
from one of their own sources a
doctrinal catechism on page 174 question
have you any at any way of proving that
the church has power to Institute
festivals of precepts answer hatching
not such power she could not have done
that in which all modern religionists
agree with her she could not have
substituted the observance of Sunday the
first day of the week for the observance
of Saturday the seventh day a change
from which there is no scriptural
Authority so the Bible prophesied that
this power that would uproot three horns
over religious conflict would persecute
other Christians
would think to change times and laws and
we have here from their own writings
that the reason most people go to church
on the first day of the week instead of
what the Bible says
is because the Catholic Church claims to
have the authority to change God's law
now you tell me coincidence a lucky
guess
a lucky guess
come on y'all think about this a lucky
guess
vague
no none of the above none of the above
and if that's not enough
we need to catch this because the Bible
says that this little horn power would
would have a period of time which the
Bible says is a time times and the
dividing of time so what is this time
times and the dividing of time according
to the Strong's Dictionary that word
time it literally means a year so a time
would be a year times would be two years
and half a time would be half a year so
that would be a total of three and a
half years
or in the Jewish year
a year is 360 days not 365.
so 360 plus 720 plus 180 360 one year
seven twenty two years 180 half a year
would equal
1260 days now please follow this
there's a there's a key to understanding
this
because we're dealing with symbolism
these days are not literal days they are
symbolic days does the bible give us a
key for understanding a symbolic day and
the answer is yes we can look in Ezekiel
chapter 4 verse 6 and see just right
there at the last part of that verse I
have appointed thee each day for a year
when it comes to symbolism a day equals
a year meaning this 1260 days
means 1260 years
this power
would persecute
would dominate would serve as the glue
would speak
great words Blasphemous words is what it
actually means against God
would persecute
all of this during a very specific
period of time that time is 1260 days
now why is it significant how does this
bring us to our second math problem well
the seat of Rome in which Justinian had
sent his General belisarius to defeat
the ostrogas their main and major battle
happened in the siege of Rome this is
where things turned for the ostrogas
this is where they were routed out of
Rome and you see the date there 5 37 to
5 38 A.D you can research this for
yourself that's the siege of Rome at the
same time the ostrogas who were Aryan
were the ones that were selecting the
popes in Rome so these were ostrogothic
Popes when when Justinian
sends belisarius to take Rome
they realize that they're gonna have to
put in popes of a different order this
is what in history is known as the
beginning of the Byzantine papacy not
the ostrogothic papacy the Byzantine
papacy in the Byzantine papacy the first
pope is a pope by the name of Pope
vigilis vigilius Pope vigilius was the
bishop of Rome from 29th of March 537 to
his death he is considered the first
pope of the Byzantine papacy now let me
just break this down just for a moment
because
the way this happened is that belisaris
removed the living pope the ostrogothic
pope before Pope vigilius
and said Pope virgilius as a new pope
he was not recognized officially
recognized by and large as the official
Pope because the other Pope was still
living well that Pope died at the in
December of 537 A.D so in a very
technical sense Pope vigilius is not
fully recognized as Pope until 5 38 but
take that time 5 37 538 this is where
Justinian's decree that had been issued
in 533
whereby the pope had been given power
that he did not have before listen to
this from Justinian's decree it says we
further ordained that in accordance with
the determinations the holy pope of
ancient Rome is the first of all the
priests the Archbishop of Constantinople
the new Rome occupies the place next
after the holy Apostolic sea of ancient
Rome and his predecessors predecessors
over the others all this is saying
is that the pope had now been given
authority over all of Rome still second
to the emperor but now he had Spiritual
Authority over a western Rome as well as
Eastern Rome
this was in essence unbridled power
if we start in 538 when justinians
decree as far as the Pope's Authority
goes into effect it could not go into
effect under the ostrogothic papacy so
if we begin in 538
and add 1 260 years
also known as the Dark Ages
we come to the year
1798 and what happens in 1798
the pope was dragged from Rome on
February 20th 1798 by Napoleon's General
berthier let me read for you
birth year and 15 000 soldiers moved
into the Papal States unopposed
and on February 10 1798
1260 years after 538 after the papacy is
given this Authority
1260 years later in 1798
birthday year Napoleon's General
encamped outside the walls of Rome three
days later birth year entered the city
and took Pope Pius VI prisoner birth
year demanded that the pope abandoned
his temporal Authority
overall
and the Papal States and leave Rome
itself for good Pious replied that his
authority had come to him from God and
could not justly abandon it birth year
resorted to force he declared the Pope
the polls and proclaimed Rome a republic
the 80 year old Pious was banished from
the city and on February 2798 French
soldiers dragged him from Rome
now you tell me you do the math
1260 years
how do you explain the accuracy of the
prophecy removing three horns the
ostrogoths uprooted out of Rome
in 538 A.D there's a new papacy because
of Justinian with a decree giving the
papacy unbridled power
and exactly 1260 years later
the Papal States are abolished
do you see the mathematic problem here
for an agnostic for an atheist who
claims that prophecy doesn't exist that
you can't you know there's no such thing
as genuine prophecy all the Prophecies
of the Bible because all you have heard
were those prophecies about look the
Bible says that Jesus would come at this
time and look he came at this time or
prophecies that make no sense that
cannot be added up
because those people presenting those
prophecies
unfortunately don't understand what
they're talking about
and so they're making stuff up about
prophecy oh Israel was restored as a
nation when there is no I'm not going to
go on a tangent let me just let me just
leave that alone okay let me leave that
alone right now
do y'all see this
1260 years this brings us beloved to our
third mathematical problem our third
prophecy which is the prophecy of
Revelation chapter 11. I'm gonna try to
get to the through these last two
prophecies as quickly as I can so bear
with me
this prophecy is especially significant
for atheists and agnostics
the Bible says in Revelation 11.
and there was given me a read like on
tour rod and the angel stood saying rise
and measure the temple of God and the
Altar and then that worship therein but
the court which is without the temple
leave out and measure it not for it is
given unto the Gentiles and the holy
city shall they tread underfoot 40 and
two months
so what I want you to see here in this
third mathematical problem is that the
same math is presented 42 months how
long is 42 months it's actually
1260 days so what I want you to see here
is that we're talking about the very
same time period here
the the the the treading underfoot for
42 months represents the persecution the
same time of persecution spoken of by
about the little horn
so when we read it is given unto the
Gentiles and they shall tread on tread
under the holy city 40 in two months we
know the holy city is not talking about
Jerusalem the holy city is symbolic of
God's people
and they are being tread underfoot or
persecuted for this time period now I'm
not going to get into all the details of
this prophecy I only want to give you
enough to establish that we know what
we're talking about
we can spend a whole another session on
every line of this prophecy but we don't
have time to do that so I'm trying to
I'm kind of cutting to the chase here to
let you see we're talking about the same
time period the Gentiles here are in
reference to that same little horn power
during the Dark Ages
so here's what we read in verse 3 and I
will give power unto my two witnesses
and they shall prophesy a thousand two
hundred and three score days in
sackcloth what is a thousand two hundred
and three score days it is the very same
time period as the 42 months as the time
times and half a time it's a thousand
two hundred and three score means 60
1260 days these are prophetic days a day
for a year
now please
we need to ask ourselves who are these
two witnesses
because we know that humans don't live
for 1260 years so who could these two
witnesses possibly be well look at how
the verse goes on or the chapter goes on
to describe them these have power to
shut Heaven that it rain not in the days
of their prophecy and have power over
Waters to turn them to blood and to
Smite the Earth with all plagues as
often as they will
so let's break this down this is very
simple
number one because we know the time
period we know we're not talking about
two people because people don't live a
thousand two hundred and sixty years
these two witnesses are symbolic of
something what are they symbolic of well
if you look at
how they're described
these have power to shut the heavens
that it rain not and have power to turn
water into blood
what the prophecy is doing here is it is
reminding you of two
individuals
specifically who are they
the Bible says Elijah was a man subject
to like passions as we are and he prayed
earnestly that it might not rain and in
Rain not on the Earth by the space of
three years in six months so Elijah
Was An Old Testament prophet
who performed a miracle when he prayed
that it would not Reign for a certain
period of time
so the Bible is pointing us to
Elijah as a prophet and then was there
someone else who turned water the blood
in the Old Testament the answer is yes
it was Moses you see there Nexus 7 20
that Moses turned the water to blood it
was one of the plagues that was brought
upon Egypt so is the Bible saying here
that Elijah and Moses are going to come
again and prophesy for 1260 years no no
no no no here's what it's saying listen
carefully we're not talking about two
people
this is symbolic and what is it symbolic
of listen to what Jesus himself said
think not that I'm come to destroy the
law
that would be symbolic of Moses or the
prophets Eliza I'm not come to destroy
but to fulfill so what is this term the
law and the prophets mean it's the word
of God
it's the word of God watch this
what does the word of God given to us
for the Bible says search the scriptures
for in them you think you have eternal
life and these are they which testify of
me what do Witnesses do Witnesses
testify
what the prophecy is telling us is that
these two witnesses who prophesied or
witnessed for 1 260 years in sackcloth
meaning under duress
represent the Bible the Old in the New
Testament well Pastor how can that even
be well listen remember that this same
church prohibited anybody from owning a
Bible from having a Bible if you had a
Bible in your possession you were burned
at the stake by the way one of the
reasons why so many people have turned
away from the Bible altogether is
because of what the church did during
the Dark Ages
what they claim to do in the name of
Jesus one of those things was that they
kept the two the witnesses the old and
the New Testament the law and the
testimony they kept the witnesses away
from the people so that's why the Bible
says that I that these two witnesses
would do their work in a hiding
under the rest if you will for this time
period
we know that people who wanted to read
the Bible on their own were risking
their lives to do so the two witnesses
are the Old and New Testament and this
is what was keeping the true gospel
alive during this period of darkness and
persecution
so notice now I'm going somewhere we're
looking here at math
the Bible says and when they shall have
finished their testimony in other words
around the ending of the 1260 years
the Bible says and when they shall have
finished their testimony the Beast that
ascendeth out of the bottomless pit
shall make war against them and shall
overcome them and kill them now remember
this here I said this is this particular
prophecy is
extremely significant for atheists and
agnostic as you remember we know that a
beast
represents a nation a kingdom
so what are we looking for here
we're looking for a kingdom
who at the end of this 1260-year period
would wage war
against the Bible officially as a nation
now my question to you is is history
history Geeks history Scholars
was there a kingdom was there a nation
that towards the end of the 1700s
declared open war on the Bible
on religion on Christianity
yes or no
come on y'all yes or no
let me read on before we get into this
answer let me read something else that
it tells us about the location of this
Beast it's a beast it rises out of an
abyss so keep that in mind this is
symbolic the Beast is not literal the
abyss is not literal it's a beast that
rises out of the deep out of the Abyss
notice what it says in Revelation 11 and
they're dead bodies meaning these two
witnesses
and their dead bodies shall lie in the
street of the great city which
spiritually is called Sodom and Egypt
now Paul's right here for a second
Sodom was known for its lawlessness
Egypt was known for its Defiance against
God remember pharaoh who is God that I
should obey him so wherever we're
talking whatever Nation this is we will
see the elements of lawlessness and a
Defiance towards God as well as open war
against the word of God open war against
Christianity open war against the Bible
it would occur sometime at the end of
the 1700s and my question to you is what
nation fits this bill did this happen
the answer is yes it happened in what we
have come to know as the French
Revolution
the French Revolution
1789 the reign of terror of the French
Revolution
established a state which was anti-roman
catholic christian in nature they were
anti-religious they were anti-god the
reason for the French Revolution one of
the reasons for the French Revolution is
because the people had become fed up
with the work of the little horn during
the
1260 years the Bible tells us here
I shouldn't say the Bible I should say
secular history tells us that there was
a de-christianization of France during
the French Revolution come on y'all
you can't make this up
this is absolutely mind-blowing now I
need you to watch this
the Bible says in the beginning Genesis
1 in the beginning God created the
Heaven and the Earth and the Earth was
without form and void and darkness was
upon the face of the deep and the spirit
of God moved upon the face of the word
as we as Christian Believers go back to
the Book of Genesis back to the abyss to
talk about how the world was created and
we say that it was created by God
the French Revolution is where atheism
made its public
entrance on the stage if you will now
I'm not saying atheism didn't exist
before this what I'm saying is that
never before had a had a had a an entire
nation raised itself up to say we reject
the god of Christianity we reject the
Bible and in place of believing that in
the beginning God created we're going to
start teaching that in the beginning
there was a big bang
no God
in fact it was during the French
Revolution that the calendar was changed
from a seven day week
the Bible to attend a week
and you have this thing called the reign
of terror in which
multitudes were killed
and again I gotta simply ask a question
how do we explain that the Bible
prophesies the rise of atheism the
rejection of the word of God
at the very time of the French
Revolution at the end of this
1260 year period how do you explain that
math I will leave that problem with you
as we go to our fourth and final problem
Revelation chapter 13. the Bible says in
Revelation 13 1 and I stood upon the
sand of the sea and saw a beasts rise
above the sea having seven heads and ten
horns and upon his horns ten crowns and
upon his head's the name of blasphemy
and the Beast which I saw was like unto
a leopard and his feet were as a feet of
a bear and his mouth is a mouth of a
lion and the dragon gave him his power
and his seat and great Authority now you
may not even realize whoa I understand
this but you understand this
because what John is talking about here
and by the way John wrote the Book of
Revelation so this is now a different
person from Daniel so mathematic problem
number three Revelation 11 and
mathematic problem number four
revelation 13.
is given to us courtesy John the
Revelator so now we got two different
people
who are somehow mysteriously
giving us this math
that cannot be explained
by the laws of nature or science
John the Revelator is simply describing
the very same Beast that Daniel saw but
he sees it as one Beast he is looking
back
Babylon media Persia Greece Rome this
little horn who got its seat
from the Emperors of Rome got its power
from the Emperors of Rome
and he goes on to say he's basically
kind of recapping everything we just saw
and I saw one of his heads as it were
wounded to death that's the paper that's
the little horn
wounded to death wounded as if it were
dead but his deadly wound was healed and
all the world wandered after the Beast
the Bible is telling us here that
despite what happened in 1798 this
deadly wound to the papacy that it would
regain power and I simply want to ask
you has that happened
has the papacy regained the power it
lost when Napoleon came in and abolished
the Papal States
I'll leave that question for you to
answer
but Revelation 13 comes down to our very
time in a very important way I need
y'all to follow this
in Revelation chapter 13
the Bible says and I beheld another
Beast coming up out of the earth he had
two horns like a lamb and he speak as a
dragon now let's break this down we know
that a beast represents a nation
so now we're looking at another Nation
coming on the scene
this nation is rising at the time that
the first Beast received its deadly Moon
so what time is that it's around the
late 1700s we're looking for a nation
that would come upon the scene
that would have their horns like a lamb
now I got a question for you and I'm
sure atheist agnostics you would know
this who does the lamb represent in the
Bible
the lamb is symbolic of Christ so what
kind of nation would this be then it
would be a professed
Christian Nation however the Bible says
it would speak like a dragon so
we're looking for a nation that would
come on the scene at the end of the
1700s that would claim through its act
that would claim through his mouth to to
be a lamb but would actually speak like
a dragon would be hypocritical
to its Christian profession
so I got a question for you can you
think of any Nation coming on the scene
in the late 1700s
that would be a professed Christian
Nation but from its very Inception
would be doing things and enacting
policies
that would reveal a dragon-like spirit
you help me
what nation can you think of that would
fit this description
interesting that our Declaration of
Independence is in 1776.
interesting that our first president
interesting that our constitution
written in 1787 ratified in 1788 in
operations since
1789. interesting that this nation at
that so many people claim
to be a Christian Nation
in its origin and its Inception
dealt in slavery
think with me the Trail of Tears
professing to be Christian and yet
speaking like a dragon
you help me with the math y'all
how does
John the Revelator
who mostly believe the Book of
Revelation was written in 95 A.D
but if you want to put it to 300 A.D
help me help me to understand
the accurate foretelling of the rise of
America the time of the rise of America
the nature of the rise of America and
then the prophecy goes on to State
listen the prophecy goes on to state
that he exercised this Beast
exercise all the power of the first
Beast before him and cause the Earth and
them that dwell therein to worship the
first Beast whose deadly wound was
healed now you tell me
who was the first Beast we already saw
that the first Revelation 11 Revelation
13 sorry the same chapter in the first
piece representing the papacy which was
a church State system the Bible says
that this nation is going to exercise
the power of the first Beast meaning is
going to attempt
to replicate
a church
state government and I would simply ask
you
can you look around today
can you look in the last 20 30 years
and identify
this very element the desire of many
so-called Christians to attempt to
implement
a theocracy
in the name of Jesus and the Bible is
warning
of the detriment of that action
I mean you would think the Bible would
warn Beware of the atheists Beware of
the Skeptics
Skeptics and atheists are mostly so
because of the actions of Christians
so-called Christians
and lo and behold the books of Daniel in
Revelation are not pointing to atheists
as the prime threat to humanity but
Christians who claim to be following
Jesus but are yet speaking and acting
like a dragon who are demanding that
others worship as they worship otherwise
you will be punished
we are seeing that happen today in real
time just go to Amazon Prime just Google
Christian nationalism and see the amount
of books coming up on this subject see
the amount of people Skeptics atheists
agnostics who are warning of this rise
of Christian nationalism not realizing
that what they are doing is echoing the
warning of the Bible
not just presented you four mathematical
problems number one two thousand years
of History whether you want to go 21 or
26 100 Years of history in Daniel 2.
number two the 1260-year time period of
Daniel 7. number three the fact that at
the end of the 1260 years there will be
a revolution based on anti-christian
sentiment and number four Revelation 13
there would be another Revolution a rise
of another Nation based on so-called
Christian principles
how do we explain all of this accurate
history from the books of Daniel and
Revelation written thousands of years
ago how do we explain the mathematical
accuracy
how do we explain the
prophetic
utterance regarding the rise of
Christian nationalism in this nation
no the Bible doesn't say Amer doesn't
say the name America no it doesn't say
the name France
but how do we describe the accuracy of
such prophecies now this is our last
slide we're done we're done
here's a question for the atheist in
agnostic
is this replicable by anyone else
can we go to the Quran and find such
prophecies can we go to you choose the
holy book can we go to any other holy
book and find this level of Prophecy by
the way
in the book of Isaiah 41 42 43 44 45 46
God issues a challenge he says look call
all your Gods together and let them tell
you the future if they can tell you the
future let them be God God himself
uses prophecy
as a determined
between who is a true God and who are
false gods non-existent gods
so the question is
can you meet this challenge
can you find
in the Prophecies of Nostradamus the
Quran you choose your book
The Book of Mormon can you find
prophecy that can be verified by history
with timestamps
mathematical timestamps
what you're going to find that is very
odd is that there's only a certain group
of people that appear to have this
ability
and they all happen to be
Prophets
of the same God
Daniel
John
Jeremiah
Isaiah
Moses
I know some of those prophecies that
some of those props are named deal with
internal prophecies I get it that's why
we didn't touch Isaiah or Jeremiah or
Moses we just dealt with Daniel and
Revelation the two most convi the two
books that are most
have the most powerful evidence of
divine intelligence of the future
do these prophets reveal their sources
the answer is yes and not one of them
say it's an inaneability all of them
point back
to the God not of the Quran
not of this holy book not of that holy
book they all point to the god of the
Bible
so now our question is do we have any
reason to believe that they're lying if
they did not lie about the future
do we have any reason to believe that
they are lying about where they have the
where they got this ability from
and if we don't have any reason to
believe they're lying
then what reason do we have to believe
that this God does not exist
now listen y'all I get it you might not
like this God that's a whole different
question
I'm not saying you have to love this God
or like this you might be like well you
know what God exists but I sure hate his
character in the Old Testament and I
don't understand this not only and hey
that's I I
that's a fair argument
but let me also say that just because
you dislike God doesn't mean that God
doesn't exist
I don't like you I don't like what I
read in the Old Testament therefore I
don't believe God exists God is evil
therefore God doesn't exist like those
two things don't go together God can
exist and also be evil
it could be an evil God
I don't believe that
but what I'm simply saying is this
if I told you 50 things that were going
to happen
I said I want you to believe me and
everything I say and you're like man bro
you're crazy I don't even know who you
are get out of here and I'm like look
I'm gonna tell you 50 things are going
to happen over the next 20 years over
the next 10 years over the next three
months
and these are not just regular things
I'm going to give it to you in order
and you walk away like this guy's crazy
but I told you those 50 things
somehow you locked it in your mind and
one by one those things began to come to
pass just as I said
specific things things specifically
regarding you
let me ask you a question
at about thing 30 would you begin to
believe that man
whatever else he said is probably going
to come to pass would you believe that
the odds of whatever else I said would
probably happen now I don't have that
power I'm just using this as an example
listen
in that prophecy of Daniel too remember
how it said a stone was cut out without
hands that was going to come and destroy
the image that stone represents Jesus a
man coming out of the sky
I know it's a hard thing to believe
a man coming out of the sky to bring
people to heaven
it's a hard thing to believe
so God says I'm going to show you all
the things that are going to happen
before that I'm going to show you
Babylon middle Persia Greece Rome I'm
going to show you Rome breaking down in
the various tribes I'm going to show you
this this uh
Spirit spiritual Kingdom that is going
to come on the scene just around this
time and is going to do things that I
that I do not approve of I'm going to
show you that as a result of what this
kingdom does it's going to bring about
atheism at the end of that time period
I'm going to show you that there's going
to be another kingdom that rises on the
scene at that very same time that's
going to try to do the very same thing
that was done in the dark ages in the
name of Jesus and I haven't even gotten
into how it's all going to end but I'm
showing you this to let you know that if
these things came to pass you can pretty
much trust that that stone that is cut
out without hands that is going to come
inside the image that's probably going
to happen
what reason do you have
not to believe
there's your challenge
may God bless you as you take this
challenge
and if you fail this challenge
may God bless you
as you grab hold of his word
and allow him
to guide your future
[Music]